

3024 Franklin Corner Lane, Herndon, VA (Permanent) 0B35 Lee Hall 570 Wash. St. SW, Blacksburg VA (Temp) 760-206-3416

ankit.deshmukh@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Currently a student in the College of Engineering at Virginia Tech with over 5 years of experience in Computer Science. I enjoy the problem solving and logical components that CS provides. I am always looking for new ways to expand my knowledge and entertaining projects to start or join. I am currently looking for a summer internship where I can leverage my problem solving skills to gain real world experience and extend my skillset.

EXPERIENCE

2016 – present

Silkops

Intern

Reformatting their website using Dart, Javascript, and MaterializeCSS to create a lighter and faster version. Worked on using Dart within MaterializeCSS.

2016 – present

Virginia Tech Parking Mobile App

Developer

Updating the Virginia Tech website using Javascript and ReactJS to tie ArcGIS (GPS API System) data to the app and respond to users selections. This allows users to filter the results based on selection criteria.

2014 - 2016

Steven F. Udvar-Hazy Center

Volunteer

Led Discovery Stations to teach information about the Aerospace program in an entertaining and informative way.

PROJECTS & RESEARCH

2015 — 2016

Driving Simulator

Partner

Created a realistic driving simulator using Oculus and MYO. When fully developed this can lead to less accidents as this provides inexperienced drivers with a way to practice off the road without the possibility of harming themselves or others. This can also provide

LINKS

Gitub:

github.com/2016adeshmukh

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/2016adeshmukh

Personal Website:

2016adeshmukh.github.io

SKILLS

Personal

Communication

Driven

Detail Oriented

Computer

С

Java

Python

Javascript

HTML/CSS

PHP

Dart

Lua

AndroidStudio/Java

React JS

Node JS

Languages

English

Spanish

Marathi

AWARDS

National Merit Scholarship Finalist AP Scholar with Distinction

National AP Scholar
TARC National Finalist

2 | Page Ankit Deshmukh

users with the opportunity to practice in varying road conditions.

2016 - Present RoomMusic

Creator

Takes in users input through a Google Spreadsheet and finds the corresponding songs on Spotify and plays through the list. This was created using Googles API, Spotify's API, and python.

2016 - Present Stock Tracker

Creator

Displays balances for a tracking portfolio and graphs selected stock performances. It uses IntrinioAPI data to get real time stock prices and monitors these daily. The user has the option to trade hypothetical stocks.

2015 - 2016 Dead Link Finder

Partner

Takes in URL's from user and recursively traverses all links on page and links within links to find and report back all dead or broken links. Idea was created due to presence of dead links on our schools website which needed to be fixed.

2013 - 2014 **Tweet Sorter**

Partner

Collects and filters local tweets using Twitter API and Java to find the most popular hashtags used in the area. Also allows the user to search within twitter and find a specified user's most used word.

For all other work please check Github

EDUCATION

2016 - present Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Current GPA: 3.91

Virginia Tech - Anticipated Graduation 2019

2012 - 2016 Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Tech

Graduated with Advanced Studies Diploma